TEMITOPE ABISOLA

+447771053907 | United Kingdom | abisolatemitope38@gmail.com

http://www.linkedin.com/in/temitopeabisola, https://github.com/Maltigold

CAREER OBJECTIVE

A Broadminded Data Scientist and Machine Learning Engineer with proficiency working with Python and its ecosystem, R, SQL, and other data tools for data analysis, forecasting, predicting, and visualizing. Experienced in developing and deploying cutting-edge machine learning models and algorithms to drive business growth and optimize decision-making processes and motivated to take on new initiatives as an individual and part of a team, utilizing data science/machine learning skills including algorithm designs and data structures to solve problems.

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN DATA SCIENCE

September 2022- September 2023

Manchester Metropolitan University, Manchester, United Kingdom

Key Modules: Principles of Data Science, Machine Learning Concepts, Computational Math Analysis and Statistics, Advanced Machine Learning, Data Management and Governance, Deep Learning, Algorithms & Data Structures, Big Data.

- Strong Knowledge and skills to acquire, curate, manage, and analyze data for solving real-world problems.
- Transferable computational and statistical thinking skills to create and deploy data-driven products.
- Able to communicate findings and address any legal or ethical questions that come with data processing.

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN INDUSTRIAL CHEMISTRY

October 2014-November 2018

- Oduduwa University, Osun Nigeria.
 - Strong foundation in problem-solving and critical thinking skills.
 - Developed effective communication skills for presenting technical information to diverse audiences.

EXPERIENCE

WORK EXPERIENCE

DATA ANALYST— Stellar Beverages

August 2020 – September 2022

- Collected and analyzed data from various sources to identify trends, patterns, and insights related to manufacturing processes and production output.
- Developed and maintained databases, spreadsheets, and other data management systems to organize and store manufacturing data.
- Used data visualization tools, such as graphs and charts, to communicate insights and findings to stakeholders clearly and concisely.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, such as engineering, production, and quality control, to identify areas for improvement and make recommendations for process optimization.
- Developed and implemented data-driven solutions to improve manufacturing efficiency, productivity, and quality.
- Monitored key performance indicators (KPIs) to assess manufacturing processes' success and identify improvement areas.

Account Officer— Access Bank Plc

January 2020 - July 2020

- Boosted business acquisition with strategic prospecting initiatives and favorable partnerships.
- Served as the primary contact for client service teams for several projects.
- Developed reports to inform operational strategy and decision-making.
- Optimized Investment portfolios to support client objectives and reduced company and client risk through credit application processes and review of approval criteria.
- Reduced company and client risks through credit application processes and approval/denial criteria review.
- Managed and maintained current retail business relationships and sought new accounts through sales.
- Analyzed financial statements and cash flow forecasts to inform operational strategy and decision-making.
- Met budget target through revenue and profit generation.

SALES & REPORTING ANALYST — Nigerian Bottling Company (Coca-Cola) July 2017 - October 2017

- Assessed the processes related to the reporting area, seeking opportunities to improve and drive data quality.
- Reported sales using data to provide insights that support the decision-making and strategic planning of NBC's Sales
 Team.
- Collated weekend & public holiday credit artifacts on behalf of the region for finance to apply to customer accounts.
- Collaborated with stakeholders to deliver mission-critical time-bound reports accurately.

PROJECTS EXPERIENCE

Machine Learning Engineer Project

PROXY MACHINE LEARNING MODELS FOR EXPLAINABILITY

July 2023 – September 2023

Tech-stack: Python, Pandas, Numpy, PyTorch, Seaborn, Sckit-learn, Matplotlib, OverLeaf, Git.

- Conducted extensive research, and created and implemented a machine learning model capable of explaining and providing transparent insights into the decision-making process of complex machine learning models.
- A black-box model (complex machine learning models) was built and then the prediction output of the black-box model to train the proxy models.
- The best-performing proxy model after it was trained with the black-box predictions output was the "Decision Tree Model" which explains 88% of the variance of the black-box predictions output with MAE Of 17611.20.

Data Scientist/Machine Learning Engineer

CAR PRICE PREDICTION

June 2023 - July 2023

- In this project, the primary objective was to effectively leverage a database containing anonymized vehicle advertisements and to predict the price of a car given some parameters.
- By Seamlessly integrating data preprocessing, feature engineering, optimal regression model selection, and comprehensive interpretability analysis, this project accomplished a nuanced understanding of vehicle price prediction, bolstered by the successful deployment of advanced machine learning techniques.

Robotic-Assisted Surgery in Healthcare

Prediction of Diabetic Retinopathy from Fundus Photography Images of Patients Using Deep Learning Algorithms PROJECTS DONE WITH EXCEL

Sales Report, Dashboard Creation, Data Analysis, Budget Tracker, Financial Modeling...

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, R, SQL, C#
- Tools: Jupyter Notebook, Microsoft Power BI, Excel, VS Code, MySQL, Google Collaboratory Notebook, Linux.
- Frameworks: NumPy, SciPy, Matplotlib, Pandas, Scikit-learn, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Map-reduce, Apache Spark.
- Data Processing: Data cleaning and analysis, Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Data governance, Database querying, and management.

AWARDS/CERTIFICATIONS

- Data Camp Associate Data Scientist (In-view)
- Google Skills for Africa: Data Analytics.
- Udemy.com; User Experience Design (UX), HTML, Python, and SQL.
- Google Skills for Africa; Digital Marketing Course, Customer Relationship Management